<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DocConceptRoot xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" UniqueId="41eaecf1-7d8d-40a5-8aa9-619941571384">
	<ApplicableEntity xsi:type="DocEntity" xsi:nil="true" href="IfcBeamType" />
	<Concepts>
		<DocTemplateUsage Name="Material Profile Set" UniqueId="1c07d75c-8e12-43e0-a16a-bbca6550976b">
			<Documentation>&lt;p&gt;The material of the &lt;em&gt;IfcBeamType&lt;/em&gt; is defined by the &lt;em&gt;IfcMaterialProfileSet&lt;/em&gt; or as fall back by &lt;em&gt;IfcMaterial&lt;/em&gt; and attached by the &lt;em&gt;IfcRelAssociatesMaterial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.RelatingMaterial&lt;/em&gt;. It is accessible by the inverse &lt;em&gt;HasAssociations&lt;/em&gt; relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;
NOTE&amp;nbsp; It is illegal to assign an &lt;em&gt;IfcMaterial&lt;/em&gt; to an &lt;em&gt;IfcBeamType&lt;/em&gt;, if there is at least one occurrence of &lt;em&gt;IfcBeamStandardCase&lt;/em&gt; for this type.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shared profile definition is defined by assigning an &lt;em&gt;IfcMaterialProfileSet&lt;/em&gt; (see material use definition above). The &lt;em&gt;IfcMaterialProfile&lt;/em&gt; refers to the subtype of &lt;em&gt;IfcProfileDef&lt;/em&gt; that is the common profile for all beam occurrence, if used. It is only applicable if the &lt;em&gt;IfcBeamType&lt;/em&gt; has only occurrences of type &lt;em&gt;IfcBeamStandardCase&lt;/em&gt; (see definition of &lt;em&gt;IfcBeamStandardCase&lt;/em&gt; for further information).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;
NOTE&amp;nbsp; The attribute &lt;em&gt;ProfileName&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;IfcProfileDef&lt;/em&gt; subtype, referenced in &lt;em&gt;IfcMaterialProfile&lt;/em&gt; should contain a standardized profile name according to local standards. However, an additional geometric representation of the profile is necessary (such as &lt;em&gt;IfcExtrudedAreaSolid&lt;/em&gt;). An importing application is allowed to check for the existence of the profile name: in case of identifying it as a standardized name, the corresponding profile geometry and possibly other cross sectional properties can be read from a library. Otherwise the geometric representation and possible non geometric &lt;em&gt;IfcProfileProperties&lt;/em&gt; have to be used.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</Documentation>
			<Definition xsi:type="DocTemplateDefinition" xsi:nil="true" href="Material_Profile_Set_12Ui1LAd52mgGZSMYVfrnP" />
			<Exchanges>
				<DocExchangeItem Applicability="export" Requirement="optional">
					<Exchange xsi:type="DocExchangeDefinition" xsi:nil="true" href="Design_Transfer_Exchange_34c6WDp8j0Cgdpp6il2Mz2" />
				</DocExchangeItem>
				<DocExchangeItem Applicability="import" Requirement="optional">
					<Exchange xsi:type="DocExchangeDefinition" xsi:nil="true" href="Design_Transfer_Exchange_34c6WDp8j0Cgdpp6il2Mz2" />
				</DocExchangeItem>
			</Exchanges>
		</DocTemplateUsage>
	</Concepts>
	<ApplicableTemplate xsi:type="DocTemplateDefinition" UniqueId="7996fb37-43c8-400f-9c27-63b3a125bf13" Type="IfcBeamType" />
</DocConceptRoot>

